Guide to the Andrew Dickson White papers, 1832-1919.
White, Andrew Dickson papers, 1832-1919
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Andrew Dickson White papers, 1832-1919.
1-2-2
Andrew Dickson White, 1832-1918.
99.2 cubic ft.,
Correspondence, lectures, speeches, articles, manuscripts, financial records, clippings, photographs, engravings, diplomas, memorabilia, family documents, diaries, and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection consists of papers relating to White's activities as educator, politician, and diplomat.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Andrew D. White was born in 1832 in Homer, New York. He attended Geneva College, (now Hobart College), Geneva, New York, and Yale University, graduating in Yale's class of 1853. After teaching history and English literature at the University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, he was elected to the New York State Senate, and served as senator for the Syracuse area from 1864 to 1867. There he met Ezra Cornell, and as chairman of the Senate Education Committee, he became involved in efforts to charter Cornell University as the state's land grant college. The bill chartering Cornell University was passed in April 1865; White became the University's first president in 1866. White was instrumental in developing the history and political science departments at Cornell, and took special interest in the library and the architecture of the new university. His 20-year tenure as University president was interrupted by a visit to Santo Domingo with a Presidential commission in 1871, by a European tour from 1876 to 1878, and by a term as United States Minister to Berlin from 1879 to 1881. White resigned the University presidency in 1885, and traveled extensively in Europe. After the death of his first wife, Mary Amanda Outwater, he gave a lecture tour in the United States, returned to Europe, and finally joined Willard Fiske for a journey to Egypt, Greece and Turkey.
In September 1890, White married Helen Magill, the daughter of Swarthmore College President Edward Hicks Magill, and the first woman to receive the Ph.D. in the United States. White served in many diplomatic roles, as Minister to Russia from 1893 to 1894 and Ambassador to Germany from 1897 to 1902. He was president of the American delegation to the Peace Conference at The Hague in 1899. White returned to Ithaca in 1904, where he remained until his death in 1918. He authored many books, including A History of the Warfare of Science with Theology in Christendom, and other articles and essays.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection consists of incoming correspondence, manuscripts of lectures, speeches and articles; manuscripts of presidential reports; manuscripts of books; copies of publications; financial records; clippings; photographs, engravings, diplomas and memorabilia; family documents and diaries. Also, some of White's outgoing correspondence including his letters to Charles Kendall Adams, Cornell University's second president, and William Channing Russel, Andrew D. White's vice president; correspondence and dispatches from White during his service as Envoy Extraordinary and Minister Plenipotentiary to Germany, and later as Ambassador to Russia; diplomatic instructions from the U.S. Department of State; correspondence from George Frederick William Holls on various topics of state, national and international politics, and correspondence pertaining to the American Academy of Arts and Letters. Also, correspondence relating to family affairs and finances, White's college days at Hobart College and Yale University, his professorship at the University of Michigan, his service in the New York State legislature, the founding and administration of Cornell University, educational ideas, civil service reform, the policies and activities of the Republican Party, the proposed annexation of Santo Domingo, and the study and writing of history and the study of art and architecture.
Personal correspondence includes letters from or about many family members, including Andrew White Newberry, Arthur Cleveland Newberry, Clara White Newberry, Spencer B. Newberry, Emily Outwater, Lucia Phillips Outwater, Andrew Danforth White, Andrew Dickson White II, Andrew Strong White, Ann Bruce White (Mrs. Frederick Davies), Frederick Davies White, Hamilton Salisbury White, Helen Magill White, Hilda White, Horace Keep White II and Horace Keep White III, Karin Andreevna White, and Mary Outwater White. Also, drafts of White's will drawn by Mynderse Van Cleef. Other correspondents include people involved with Cornell University such as Liberty Hyde Bailey, George Lincoln Burr, Ezra Cornell, Hiram Corson, Daniel Willard Fiske, Francis Miles Finch, Hiram Sibley, Henry W. Sage, Goldwin Smith, Robert H. Thurston, Moses Coit Tyler and other members of the Board of Trustees and faculty; historical and literary figures such as Lord Acton, Herbert Baxter Adams, Lord Bryce, Andrew Carnegie, Theodore Dreiser, Charles William Eliot, Ulysses S. Grant, Justin Smith Morrill, Theodore Roosevelt, Leo Tolstoy, Hendrik Willem van Loon, Queen Victoria, Booker T. Washington and Woodrow Wilson.
Letter from White to the Cornell University Board of Trustees about the placement of the White Library, 1887.
Also, miscellaneous notes and lists on the French Revolution and Napoleon Collection; list of contemporary imprints; index to autographs; and various prose miscellany. Includes a White family genealogy. Also, a letter from Andrew Dickson White to Rabbi Joseph Krauskopf, March 27, 1911.
SUBJECTS
Names:
White, Andrew Dickson, 1832-1918.; Acton, John Emerich Edward Dalberg Acton, 1834-1902.; Adams, Charles Kendall, 1835-1902.; Adams, Herbert Baxter, 1850-1901.; Bailey, L. H. (Liberty Hyde), 1858-1954.; Bryce, James Bryce, 1838-1922.; Burr, George Lincoln, 1857-1938.; Carnegie, Andrew, 1835-1919.; Cornell, Ezra, 1807-1874.; Corson, Hiram, 1828-1911.; Eliot, Charles William, 1834-1926.; Finch, Francis M. (Francis Miles), 1827-1907.; Fiske, Willard, 1831-1904.; Grant, Ulysses S. (Ulysses Simpson), 1822-1885.; Holls, Frederick William, 1857-1903.; Krauskopf, Joseph, 1858-1923.; Morrill, Justin S. (Justin Smith), 1810-1898.; Newberry, Andrew White.; Newberry, Arthur Cleveland.; Newberry, Clara White.; Newberry, Spencer B.; Outwater, Emily.; Outwater, Lucia Phillips.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919.; Russel, William Channing.; Sage, Henry W. (Henry Williams), 1814-1897.; Sibley, Hiram, 1807-1888.; Smith, Goldwin, 1823-1910.; Thurston, Robert Henry, 1839-1903.; Tolstoy, Leo, 1828-1910.; Tyler, Moses Coit, 1835-1900.; Van Cleef, Mynderse, 1853-1935.; Van Loon, Hendrik Willem, 1882-1944.; Victoria, 1819-1901.; Washington, Booker T., 1856-1915.; White family.; White, Andrew Danforth, 1874-1877.; White, Andrew Dickson, 1832-1918.; White, Andrew Dickson, 1888-1907.; White, Andrew Strong, 1867-1952.; White, Ann Bruce.; White, Frederick Davies, 1859-1901.; White, Hamilton Salisbury, 1853-1899.; White, Helen Magill, 1853-1944.; White, Hilda, 1891-1892.; White, Horace Keep, ca.1837-1915.; White, Horace Keep, 1865-1943.; White, Karin Andreevna, 1893-1971.; White, Mary Outwater, 1836-1887.; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924.; American Academy of Arts and Letters.; Cornell University--Administration.; Cornell University--Buildings.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University--History.; Cornell University--Libraries.; Cornell University--Planning.; Cornell University--Presidents.; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University.Board of Trustees.; Hobart College.; National Republican Party (U.S.); New York (State). Legislature.; Republican Party (N.Y.); United States. Dept. of State.; University of Michigan.; Yale University.
Subjects:
Architecture--Study and teaching.; Civil service--Law and legislation.; Diplomacy.; Education.; Higher education and state.; Politics, Practical.; Politics and education.; History--Study and teaching.; College teachers.; Diplomats.
Places:
Europe--Politics and government.; Germany--Description and travel.; Russia--Description and travel.; Santo Domingo (Dominican Republic); United States--Diplomatic and consular service--Germany.; United States--Diplomatic and consular service--Soviet Union.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Diplomas.; Manuscripts for publication.; Photographs.; Reports.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Much of the correspondence was microfilmed and the microfilm has since been digitized and is available as part of this collection here.
A published guide to the microfilm is available by clicking here. 4MB PDF.
Access Restrictions:
Boxes 247-252 (MU-1935-1984) require staff member to be present.
MU-1985 requires permission of the University Archivist.
RELATED MATERIALS
Includes collection 1-2-531, Albert Hazen Wright's research material on White.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
Series II. Manuscripts, Documents, and Items
Series III. Diplomatic Documents
Series IV. Diplomas, Degrees, and Certificates
Series V. Photographs
Series VI. Engravings and Lithographs
Series VII. Printed Pamphlets and Articles by A.D. White
Series VIII. Pamphlets and Booklets
Published in the United States
European and South American publishers
Rare Books and Antiquities Catalogues
Series IX. Objects and Memorabilia
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1825 - 1854 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1855 - Sept. 30, 1858 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, Oct. 1, 1858 - July 24, 1862 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, July 25, 1862 - Dec. 31, 1864 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 14, 1865 - Nov. 28, 1866 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, Nov. 29, 1866 - Jan. 24, 1868 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, Jan. 25, 1868 - Sept. 30, 1868 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, Oct. 1, 1868 - Aug. 6, 1869 (Box 8)
    Box 8 Folder 2 contains White's annotated inaugural program as well as a handwritten program describing the events of the inauguration.
  - Correspondence, Aug. 7, 1869 - July 31, 1870 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 1, 1870 - June 30, 1871 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, July 1, 1871 - Feb. 11, 1872 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, Feb. 12 - Aug. 17, 1872 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, Aug. 18, 1872 - Feb. 3, 1873 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, Feb. 4, 1873 - Sept. 13, 1873 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, Sept. 14, 1873 - Feb. 19, 1874 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, Feb. 20 - June 27, 1874 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, June 28 - Nov. 11, 1874 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, Nov. 12, 1874 - Apr. 22, 1875 (Box 18)
  - Balance Sheet, January 1, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Horace K. White, January 1, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Caleb Caulkins, January 2, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - L.S. Austin, January 2, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - J. Dewitt Miller, January 2, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Henry W. Sage, January 2, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Edward Seymour, January 2, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Warren S. Barlow, January 3, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - John C. Haynes, January 3, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - J.C. Caldwell, January 4, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - John G. Clark, January 4, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - E.W. Fuertes, January 4, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - W.G. Gannett, January 4, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - W.W. Wood, January 4, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - John E. Carroll, January 5, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - E.C. Cleaves, January 5, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - J.W. Fairchild, January 5, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    Letter. Two pages
  - H.H. Tilley, January 5, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - George J.J. Barber, January 6, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Henry B. Dawson, January 6, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Albert Jonas, January 6, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - G.L. Morris, January 6, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - John H. Rauch, January 6, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    Letter. Accompanied bill from American Public Health Association
  - S. Thurber, January 7, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - James A. Boise, January 7, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Edwin R. Plumb, January 7, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Horace K. White, January 8, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Marion S. White, January 8, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Charles Babcock, January 9, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - James A. Bailey, January 9, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - F.W. Christern, January 9, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    Letter. Accompanied a Statement of Account
  - Annie Field, January 10, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - William C. Russel, January 10, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - J.W. Dean, January 11, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Annie Field, January 11, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Martin L.B. Goddard, January 11, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - W.H. Ladd, January 11, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - John E. Sweet, January 11, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    Letter. Three pages
  - Undescribed, January 11, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    Letter. Missing page(s)
  - Albert Vide, January 11, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Dr. Bayne, January 12, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - R.P. Hallowell, January 12, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Edward J. Rich, January 12, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Joseph H. Palmer, January 13, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - J.R. Hawley, January 13, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - W.B. Phillips, January 13, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Thomas C. Strong, January 13, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Edward Seymour, January 13, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - W.W. Wood, January 13, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Charles Babcock, January 14, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - William L. Burt, January 14, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Charles W. Elliot, January 14, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - D. Lewis, January 15, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - American Clock Company (Underhill), January 18, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Edward H. Magill, January 18, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - William C. Russel, January 18, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - E. Schuyler, January 18, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - C.J. Hayden, January 19, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Sabin and Son, January 19, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Issac Salter, January 19, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Edward Seymour, January 19, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - J.L. Morris, January 21, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Albert N. Prentiss, January 21, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - J.H. Raymond, January 21, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - William C. Russel, January 21, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Charles Babcock, January 22, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Edward E. Hale, January 22, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Mrs. McDonald, January 22, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    Letter. Addressed to Mrs. White
  - B.A. Smith, January 22, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Willard Fiske, January 23, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - W.R. Rogers, January 23, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Williams Brown, January 25, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - A.B. Benham, January 25, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - C.F. Hecerll, January 25, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - J.W. Williams, January 25, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - W. Allen Butler, January 25, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - J.H. Raymond, January 25, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    Letter. Invitation to a Vassar College Social Reunion
  - Albert N. Prentiss, January 26, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Edward G. Allen, January 28, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    Letter. Addressed to Willard Fiske
  - Bancroft and Boyden, January 28, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    Letter. Two letters
  - J.S. Hunn, January 29, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - E.W. Fuertes, January 30, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - E.A. Sheddon, January 30, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Mrs. R. Christie (Box 18, Folder 17)
    Letter. Not dated
  - D.C. Gilman, January 31, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    Letter. Two copies
  - Elisabeth P. Peabody (Box 18, Folder 17)
    Letter. Two pages; not dated
  - Undescribed, January 1875 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    Sage College Memorandum. Eight pages
  - H.A.; F.O. Clark; Vaille (Box 18, Folder 17)
    Letter. Not dated; two senders
  - George H. Palmer, January 1875 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - J.W. Schermerhorn, February 1, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - John Lovell, February 2, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - J.K. Roberts, February 2, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - N.D. Phillips, February 2, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Bancroft and Boyden, February 3, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Charles J. Hayden, February 4, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Dean Sage, February 4, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Charles Babcock, February 5, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - E.H. Brown, February 5, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - D.S Hall, February 5, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    Invitation.
  - S.F. Smith, February 5, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Bancroft and Boyden, February 6, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Willard Fiske, February 6, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Sen. Roscoe Conkling, February 6, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - William C. Russel, February 7, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Willard Fiske, February 8, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Edward G. Allen, January 21, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    Invoice.
  - Mrs. J.S. Gould, February 8, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - C.H. Noab, February 8, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Edward North, February 8, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Governor Tilden, February 8, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    Invitation. Invitation to meet William Cullen Bryant
  - Andrew Dickson White, February 8, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    Letter (copy). Addressed to William Channing Gannett
  - Andrew Dickson White, February 8, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    Letter (copy). Addressed to C.J. Hayden; five pages
  - Andrew Dickson White, February 8, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    Letter (copy).
  - Irving T. Ballard, February 9, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - W.S. Barnard, February 9, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Theodore B. Comstock, February 9, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Charles J. Hayden, February 9, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Andrew Dickson White, February 9, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    Letter. Four pages
  - A. Anthony, February 10, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - A.W. Bishop, February 10, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - W.P. Blake, February 10, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    Letter. Addressed to the Executive Committee of the US Centennial Commission
  - A.R. Macdonough, February 10, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    Letter. Century Club constitution amendement
  - Andrew Dickson White, February 10, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    Letter. Six pages
  - Andrew Dickson White, February 10, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Horace K. White, February 10, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Henry Dasant, February 11, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Hunn, Spencer, & Co., February 11, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - R.O. Kellogg, February 11, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - William C. Russel, February 11, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Edward Seymour, February 11, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Andrew Dickson White, February 11, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Andrew Dickson White, February 11, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Andrew Dickson White, February 11, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    Letter. Addressed to Daniel Eilman; two pages
  - Willard Fiske, February 12, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Albert N. Prentiss, February 12, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Moses Coit Tyler, February 12, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - F.L.O. Roehrig, February 13, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    Letter. Enclosed: letter from Joseph Henry, Dec. 12, 1874
  - William C. Russel, February 13, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Issac Salter, February 13, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Wakefield Rattan Co., February 13, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Andrew Dickson White, February 13, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    Telegram (copy). Addressed to William C. Russel
  - Vincent Walsh, February 15, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Andrew Dickson White, February 15, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Frank Carpenter, February 16, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - J.H. Raymond, February 16, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - William C. Russel, February 16, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Edward Seymour, February 16, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - J. Edward Clarke, February 17, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Willard Fiske, February 17, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    Letter. Enclosed: list of ordered books, letter from Thomas Hayes to E.G. Allen
  - H.T. Morgan, February 17, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - William C. Russel, February 17, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - H.H. Tilley, February 17, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Bancroft and Boyden, February 18, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - George S. Blackie, February 18, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - W.P. Blake, February 18, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - G.C. Caldwell, February 18, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - William D. Dunning, February 18, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - John Hamilton, February 18, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - W. Harris, February 19, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Charles Tucker, February 19, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Issac Salter, February 19, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Harry H. Lockwood, February 20, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Frederick Macmillan, February 20, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - William C. Russel, February 20, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Andrew Dickson White, February 20, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    Letter. Addressed to Raiya
  - Clara Dickson White, February 21, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Sherman W. Knevals, February 22, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - William C. Russel, February 22, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Undescribed, February 23, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    List. List of books
  - Herbert H. Smith, February 23, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - William C. Russel, February 23, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Mrs. Richardson, February 24, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - G.W. Schuyler, February 24, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Andrew Dickson White, February 25, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    Postcard. Addressed to Willard Fiske
  - Edward W. Allen, February 25, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Edward W. Allen, February 25, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    Memorandum.
  - Eugene Hughes, February 25, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - William D. Dunning, February 26, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Sherman W. Knevals, February 26, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Charles Tucker, February 26, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Clara White, February 27, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    Letter. Addressed to Clara Dickson White
  - William C. Russel, February 27, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - B.E. Brewster, February 28, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Edward H. Magill, February 28, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Frank Carpenter, February 29, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Addison Boyden, March 1, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - William C. Gannett, March 1, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Hunn, Spencer, & Co., March 1, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - C.E. Watrous, March 1, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Willard Fiske, March 2, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - O.E. Fuller, March 2, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - G.W. Schuyler, March 2, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Andrew Dickson White, March 2, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Bancroft and Boyden, March 2, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Howard Clemens, March 2, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    Letter. Addressed to William C. Russel
  - Hunn, Spencer, & Co., March 3, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Albert N. Prentiss, March 3, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - William C. Russel, March 3, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Clara White, March 3, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - J.C. Abbot, March 4, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Andrew Dickson White, March 4, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Arthur Phillip Knevals, March 4, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    Telegram (copy). Copy of telegram sent by A.D. White
  - Clara Dickson White, March 4, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Clara Dickson White, March 4, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - John Clark, March 5, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    Receipt.
  - M.C. Reynolds, March 5, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Andrew Dickson White, March 6, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    Telegram. Addressed to Arthur Philip Knevals
  - Mrs. A.D. White, March 7, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    Letter. Addressed to Clara Dickson White; two pages
  - Andrew Dickson White, March 7, 1875 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    Letter. Addressed to Horace White